Benjamin Franklin Papers Part 11 -- Bonds given to the President of the United Colonies through Benjamin Franklin 1777-1782 Mss.B.F85inventory11
American Philosophical Society
Benjamin Franklin Papers Part 11 -- Bonds given to the President of the United Colonies through Benjamin Franklin
1777-1782
Mss.B.F85inventory11
American Philosophical Society
1.0 section
This is part of the large inventory for the Benjamin Franklin Papers (Mss B F85). For complete information concerning this collection, please view the Collection Description.
33 items
Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
- Bonds given to the President of the United Colonies through Benjamin Franklin upon taking out, Letters of Marque and Reprisal
  - Joshua Johnson, Jona[than] Williams [Jr.,] and Peter Collas for the bring "Franklin.", 1777 December 14; D.S. 1p.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 June 22; D.S. 1p. (Accompanied by the commission from Congress for the sloop "Alliance." S. John Hancock, President.) 1p.; Peter Amiel, ----- Poreau and ----- MacKenzie. [Not executed.]
    Scope and Contents note
    Printed.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 August 29; D.S. 2p.; Samuel Nuttle and David Chancel and fils
    for the "Dr. Franklin."
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 October 26; D.S. 2p.; John Bondfield, William Haywood and Musco Livingston
    for the "Governor Livingston."
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1779 January 9; D.S. 2p.; Joshua Johnson, Matthew Ridley and John McKirdy
    for the brig "Tom Johnson."
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1779 March 9; D.S. 2p.; John Bondfield, William Haywood and John Fulford
    for the ship "May Season."
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1779 September 18; D.S. 2p.; Joshua Lunn and Joshua Johnson
    for the brigantine "Wallace."
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1779 November 2; D.S. 1p.; Arthur Kirk and Jonathan Nesbitt
    for the schooner "Independence."
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1780 February 16; D.S. 1p.; Samuel Smith and Penet, D'Acosta freres and Cie
    for the lugger "The Kensington."
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1780 March 20; D.S. 1p.; Joshua Johnson and Jonathan Williams, Jr
    for the schooner "Betsey."
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1780 March 23; D.S. 1p.; Henry Farley, Jonathan Williams, Jr., and John Coggeshall
    for the schooner "Sally."
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1780 December 2; D.S. 1p.; Jonathan Williams, Jr., Jean Conrad Zollickoffer and James Byrne
    for the brig "Two Easters."
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1781 April 20; D.S. 3p.; Josh Shaffer and Augustus Bernard
    for the lugger "The Hazard."
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1781 May 1; D.S. 3p.; Charles Wells, Joshua Johnson, and Jonathan Williams, Jr
    for the ship "Non-Such."
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1781 August 6; D.S. 3p.; Thomas Collyer and]Peter Penet
    for the ship "Vengeance."
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1781 September 13; D.S. 3p.; Captain Cloupet and Comte de Choiseul-Gouffier
    for the brigantine "Scanderberg."
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1781 October 12; D.S. 3p.; James Tucker and John Bondfield
    for the brig "Mariana."
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1781 October 25; D.S. 1p.; George Buchanan, Joshua Johnson and Thomas Patterson
    for the ship "Favorite."
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1782 January 7; D.S, 2p.; John Angus and Simon Berard
    for the brig "Antonia."
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1782 March 8; D.S. 1p.; William Robeson, David Dickson and Jonathan Williams, Jr
    for the brigantine "Spry."
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1782 July 8; Printed D.S. 1p.; Pierre-Augustin Caron de Beaumarchais and Etienne Gregory
    for the frigate "The Alexander."
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1782 August 7; Printed D.S. 1p.; Samuel R Trevitt and Co
    for the "Argo."
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1782 August 26; D.S. 1p.; Stephen Carpenter, Joshua Johnson and Nathan Kelso
    for the brigantine "The Revolution."
    With letter of transmission from Mr. [Matthew] Ridley.
- Bonds given to the President of the United Colonies through Benjamin Franklin for the Delivery of Cargoes in the United States
  - W[illia]m Johnston, of the brigantine "Harrier," for the safe delivery of the cargo from London, 1779 November 25; D.S. 2p.
  - Walter Belt, of the brigantine "Brighton," for the safe delivery of the cargo from London, 1780 February 11; D.S. 1p.
  - Benja[min] Carpenter, of the brigantine "Adventure," for the safe delivery of the cargo from Ireland, 1780 March 14; D.S. 1p.
  - Isaac Cazneau, of the brigantine "Penelope," for the safe delivery of the cargo from England, 1780 April 16; D.S. 2p.
  - Thom[a]s Collins of the sloop "Newenham," for the safe delivery of the cargo from Dublin, 1780 September 30; D.S. 4p.
    (In duplicate and accompanied by passport.)
  - Henry Bromfield, of the "Friendship," for the safe delivery of the cargo from England, 1780 October 23; D.S. 5p.
    (Accompanied by a passport, and a notice from John Fletcher that both the passport and the bond had been destroyed, it not being thought eligible to prosecute the voyage.)
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1780 December 4; D.S. 1p.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1781 July 8; D.S. 2p.
  - Addendum, 1739 July 29; A.L.S. 1p.; Meredith, Simon
    Order to let his son, Hugh Meredith, have the sum of £8 on his account; with Hugh Meredith's receipt for the same, and for £6 more borrowed on July 30, 1739.
  - Addendum, 1739-40 January 26; A.L.S. 1p.; Dewees, William Jr
    Sent him, last week, quantity of paper. Now sends by same bearer more, to be placed to his credit.